KAMAL MINOTT

kamalminott@gmail.com

Portfolio

linkedin.com

+44 7507112479

London, United Kingdom

SUMMARY

As a Software Engineer and Professional athlete, I possess strong teamwork capabilities coupled with effective communication skills. My fascination with technology, was nurtured from a young age while watching Apple keynote speeches, which instilled in me a love for programming. I have garnered commercial coding experience in languages such as Ruby, JavaScript, React, CSS, and HTML, honing my ability to understand client needs and deliver accurate, efficient solutions. Consistently exceeding the expectations and requirements of my Project Managers and Supervisors, I remain dedicated to expanding my knowledge by continuously exploring new frameworks and implementation strategies.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Website Developer

Freelance

July 2023 - Present London, United Kingdom

Description:

- Hold consultations with clients to asses what they would want from their website.
- Design A Figma wireframe based on my clients requests.
- Research what frameworks would work best for my clients needs.
- Design website based on agreed upon frameworks and designs with the clients.
- Run tests on code base and features to ensure all code is functional prior to deployment.
- · Confirm with client that the website meets their design specifications and functionality expectations.
- Deploy website using Netlify.

British Olympic Team Fencer

Team GB

June 2017 - Present London, United Kingdom

Achievements:

- 2 x International Satellite Medalist 2024
- Ranked 1st British Fencing Cadet (U17) & Junior (U20)
- 4x National Champion
- Senior National Champion 2021
- · Commonwealth Champion 2022
- Team GB Ambition Member 2024
- Senior World Championship 2017
- · Junior World Championships 2017
- Senior European Championships 2020
- Senior European Championships 2017

Junior Technology Consultant

October 2022 - June 2023 London, United Kingdom

WeShape Tech Pathway

Whilst working at WeShape I was contracted out to several companies in which I worked on Front End Development, Back-End Development and Database Management.

Responsibilities:

- · Daily Agile Management.
- Frequent Communication with Product Owners & Team Managers.
- Bootstrap/Tailwind Front End implementation.
- · Firebase Management.
- · GitHub Repository Management.
- Team Size: 3

I have titled each of the companies I was contracted to work with during my time at WeShape:

STRENGTHS



Leading & Working in Teams

I thrive in collaborative environments. where my leadership skills shine through, I am effective in team coordination and collaboration. I foster a cohesive team spirit to achieve shared goals efficiently.



Problem-Solving & Analytical

My problem-solving skills, coupled with a keen analytical mindset, enable me to tackle complex challenges with ease. I excel in dissecting issues, identifying root causes, and implementing innovative solutions that drive impactful results.



Adaptability & Continuous Learning

Embracing change is second nature to me, as I possess a high degree of adaptability to evolving situations and technologies. I eagerly absorb new knowledge and skills, ensuring I stay at the forefront of advancements in my field.

SKILLS & YEARS OF EXPERIENCE

CSS Ruby CI/CD 2 years 2 years 2 years

Python

GitHub

Node.js Website Deployment Ruby on Rails 2 vears 2 vears

Cypress Testing

2 vears

Figma

SQL React

JavaScript

TypeScript

2 years

Cockroach DB React-Native

Agile Development нтмі

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Development

Completed via Le Wagon in December 2022

Agile Project Management & Scum Completed via OpenClassrooms in February 2023

JavaScript Certificate Completed via Mimo in November 2023

Typescript Fundamentals Course

Completed via Codecademy in November 2023

AWS Cloud Practitioner

Front-End Developer

Uptime-labs (WeShape Contracted)

May 2023 - June 2023 London, United Kingdom

Responsibilities:

- · Developed & implemented key features which resulted in an increase in user engagement.
- Used Agile Methods and principles to prioritise and manage tasks effectively, ensuring timely delivery of features.
- Team Size: 4

Web Developer

February 2023 - May 2023 London, United Kingdom

LoopNotLuck (WeShape Contracted)

Requirements: maintaining and improving the companies existing website as well as implementing features within their new website.

- Designed & styled Admin Portal using React.
- Designed Confluence pages to walk unfamiliar developers through complex technical processes.
- Implementing CI/CD pipeline using Github Actions, automating the build, testing, and. deployment procedures for streamlined website development.
- Bug fixing & Resolving Issues.
- Implementing Cypress tests to ensure websites functionality.
- Code Base Optimisation.
- Team Size: 4

Web Developer

January 2023 - February 2023 London, United Kingdom

Mentor Pathway (WeShape Contracted)

Requirements:

- Referenced Figma designs to improve Ruby-on-Rails, bootstrap and CSS Designs.
- Collaborated with team members to assess UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Team Size: 3

EDUCATION

12 GCSEs

Mathematics (A*): English (A) Double Science (AA) Spanish (C) ICT (A*)

Grades Achieved

2014 Coopers Coborn and Company School Upminster

A-Levels

Computing (A*) Computer Science (A*)

Maths (A)

University

Goldsmiths University

B.Sc Computer Science - Ongoing

AFFILIATIONS

REFERENCES Available upon request

HOBBIES

When I'm not training for fencing I often play basketball to help douse my super competitive flames, I also tend to watch a lot of tape of my previous fights to aid me in improving my technique further.